# Biswasindhu Mandal

sindhu.online.24x7@gmail.com 💟

https://artbindu.github.io/artbindu

https://in.linkedin.com/in/artbindu in

Completed graduation in Mathematics, master in Computer Science in Application and have 4+ years of experience in Frontend, Backend, and OTT Web technologies.

Specialized in JavaScript, Typescript, Node JS, Express, Mongo, MySQL, Media Player Libraries (DASH, HLS, Bitmovin), and Angular2 Framework.

### **Skills**

- Domain: JavaScript, Node JS
- Skilled in Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (es5, es6), Node.js, Angular2
- Operating System: Windows, Mac OS, Linux
- Known Programming Language and Database: C, Python, Java, C++, MongoDB, MySql, OracleDB
- Ability to work under pressure and positive attitude.
- Ability to adapt to any environment.
- Analytical thinking and ability to synthesize.
- Ability to work in Multiple Teams & maintenance a parrel work according to requirements.
- Have experience working with multiple customers.

# **Experience**

# Engineer - Software / Rebaca Technologies, Kolkata

#### **OCTOBER 2023 - PRESENT**

#### Client Project: MediaKind (Abot Automation)

ROLE	Abot Automation Testing Framework test case writing
Environment	<ul> <li>Cucumber, Selenium, Ecllipse</li> <li>Used WMC PayTV &amp; DTC, MKPlayer SDK for automation testing.</li> <li>Web Browsers (Chrome, Edge, Safari, Firefox).</li> </ul>
Methodologies	BDD
Tools	Ecllipse, VS Code, Git, Azure DevOps, Charles, NVM, Vysor

- Start working on Selenium Cucumber based Automation framework and gain basic knowledge of Abot Automation Framework and Testing Interface related project.
- Write Automation Test Script using Cucumber for DTC, PayTV & MKPlayer-SDK Playback on browser.
- Learn Agent setup and Automation related azure pipeline setup, execution and report validation.
- Transfer OTT Payer related knowledge to Automation teams specially for Automation Framework end development and validation.
- Maintains daily & impressive workflow in short time.

#### **APRIL 2023 - PRESENT**

#### Client Project: MediaKind (SME)

ROLE	•	MediaFirst PayTV Media Player bug fixing
	•	SME Customer Service on multiple platforms player issue

Environment	<ul> <li>Node JS, JavaScript, Typescript,</li> <li>Used WMC/UMC library depends on platforms</li> <li>Video Player on major Web Browsers (Chrome, Edge, Safari, Firefox), Chromecast (V2/V3), Android &amp; iOS 1ft-2ft Device, AppleTV, Multiple Set top box.</li> </ul>
Methodologies	Agile, TDD, BDD
Tools	VS Code, Git, Azure DevOps, Charles, NVM, FileZilla, WinSCP, Xcode

- Resolving bugs in MediaFirst PayTV platform, mostly for player trick modes and smooth playing related issues for LIVE, VOD, CatchUp and Recorded & InProgress DVR assets.
- Widely handling player related issue for our internal environments and multiple clients' environments like CCX, SKT, TGN, VFQ, DTP, DTC, DU.
- Completely handling all type of Chromecast V2 playback related issue and all type of receiver end custom screen related changes (CC V2 & V3) for all MediaKind clients.
- Working on multiple platforms like 1ft-2ft Android & iOS device, AppleTV & Android 10ft device, to reproduce, deep analysis and supports on the clients' issues.
- Get chance to work with multiple teams at a time depends on customer issue and provided details analysis between customer and respective team.

#### JULY 2022 - MARCH, 2023

### Client Project: MediaKind (WMC)

ROLE	OTT SDK Player Development and bug fixing - Bitmovin	
	PayTV & DTC SDK Player Development and bug fixing	
	Chromecast-V3 Receiver bug fixing	
Environment	Node JS, JavaScript, Typescript	
	Used Bitmovin player	
	HTML5 Video in Web Browsers (Chrome, Edge, Safari, Firefox), Chromecast V2/V3	
Methodologies	Agile, TDD, BDD	
Tools	VS Code, Git, Azure DevOps, Charles, NVM, FileZilla, WinSCP	

- Helped upgrade new react base WMC-SDK player Integration for DTC & PayTV SDK Library.
- Research & develop new features of player. Such as,

Dynamic STS token upgradation

Bitmovin Modular Player Integration

- Resolved bugs in the player to fixed Player trick modes and smooth playing on LIVE, VOD, Catch up and DVR assets.
- Get to chance worked on Chromecast V3 receiver development & bug fixing.
- Resolved Chromecast V2 related bugs and used Chromecast to cast media from WMC-SDK, UMC-SDK, MF PayTV
  1ft-2ft App to Chromecast V2/V3 dongle & 10ft MediaFirst PayTV App.
- Understand MediaFirst HTML5 Pay TV platform player to fixed player issue on multiple environments like Android TV and browser.
- Get chance to handling server-side code deployment.
- Update unit test case to 1500+ and Mocha-Chai framework and successfully passed more than.

#### **JUNE, 2021 – JUNE 2022**

#### Client Project: Stenograph (APEX)

ROLE	•	Design and development of APEX Web Application feature and bug fixing
	•	Design and development of APEX Admin Web Application feature and bug fixing
Environment	•	Using UI framework Angular 10
	•	Node JS and Typescript
	•	Mostly used Chrome. Otherwise, we support Edge & Firefox also.
Methodologies	Αg	gile, BDD

Tools	VS Code, Git, Azure DevOps, Visual Studio, MS SQL Server
10015	vs code, Git, Azure Devops, visual studio, ivis sqt server

- Worked as an intelligent ecosystem (APEX) that connects clients and agencies to reporters, videographers, translator and transcriptionists through Stenograph's industry-leading software, CATalyst. This empowers both parties to manage the workflow from a single application. Handling all aspects of a job, from scheduling to billing and everything in between.
- Worked on another ecosystem APEX-Admin that manages and processes all clients, agencies, reporters, videographers, transcriptionists and translators operations of APEX system. Handling billings and payments of all third-party members of clients.
- Expert knowledge in UI heuristics and principles, technical writing, business and user workflow, logical information organization, prototyping and use case scenarios.
- Resolve bugs in Web Application.
- Adding/improving new/existing features and functionality according to the customer requirements.
- Management discussions to figure out new requirement.
- Oversee and aid development activity of other developers.
- Extensive experience in UI web applications using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Typescript, JSON, Angular, Regular Expression.
- Extensively worked on Developing SOAP and REST based Application.

#### JULY 2019 - MAY, 2021

### Client Project: MediaKind (WMC)

•	
ROLE	OTT SDK Player Development and bug fixing – DASH & HLS
	WMC SDK Player Integration and bug fixing
	Chromecast-V2 Sender/Receiver Development
	OTT Media Player Unit Test Case Integration
Environment	Node JS and vanilla JavaScript
	Used players such as DASH, Native HLS
	HTML5 Video in Major Web Browsers (Chrome, IE & Edge, Safari, Firefox),
	Chromecast (casting from Web & Devices)
Methodologies	Agile, TDD, BDD
Tools	VS Code, Git, Azure DevOps, Charles, NVM, Jira

- Helped create & upgrade a custom MediaKind WMC-SDK player.
- Research and develop new features of player. Such as,
  - IHD InHome Detection
  - DAI Dynamic Advertisement Insertion
- Integrated the third-party DASH player and maintaining the existing flow of our player.
- Resolved bugs in the player to fixed Player trick modes and smooth playing on LIVE, VOD & Recording media.
- Worked in UI development to cast media via Chromecast STB & dongle and successfully managed all player trick modes.
- The unit test case was written using Mocha-Chai framework and successfully passed more than 90% of the whole project with 1200+ test cases.
- Worked in various version control system SVN, GIT, Azure DevOps.

# **Internship & Project**

JAN 2019 – JUNE 2019

### Internship / Rebaca Technologies, Kolkata

### Rebaca OAS (Office Automation System)

• Development of BE application to migrate employee data from MS-SQL to MongoDB using Vanilla JavaScript, Node JS, Express, MS-SQL and Mongo.

- Development of REST API base BE application to fetch employee data from MongoDB with different format using Vanilla JavaScript, Node JS, Express and Mongo.
- Development of FE application to show employee information in Web Browser in different aspects using Angular 8 framework with REST API.

### **FUEL App Test Automation Framework Rebaca OAS**

- Rest API base Implementation for Web.
- Framework Test script integration & testing using Cucumber.js

JAN 2019 - MAY 2019

### Project / Jadavpur University, Kolkata

### **Analysis of Indian Rainfall Data for Future Prediction**

This is a methodology for forecasting rainfall in all regions in India. Filter input data and apply ANN to forecast Future data using Python, MongoDB, NumPy, Matplotlib.

**NOV 2018 - DEC 2018** 

### **Project**

### Online e-book Shopping Cart

JSP Servlet project for "Online e-book Shopping Cart".

Used Database (Oracle10g), Back-End (Java8, JSP), Front-End (HTML, CSS, JavaScript).

### **Education**

## **CSE / Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India**

Masters of Computer Application – 2019 – 67.22%

### **B.Sc.** / Vidyasagar University, Midnapore, India

Mathematics Honours - 2015 - 62.12%

### **Higher Secondary / WBCHSE, West Bengal**

Science Stream - 2010 - 71.20%

# Secondary / WBBSE, West Bengal

General - 2008 - 73.87%

# **Activities**

Date of Birth 24 – April – 1993

Gender Male Nationality Indian

Languages English (Professional Working), Hindi (Limited Working)

Bengali (Full Professional), Oriya (Elementary)

Hobbies Reading Detective Books, Cycling, Playing Card, Cricket